Example Searches

John Smith

mail@example.com

123 Main St, Pasadena, CA

(626) 555-5555

John Smith, Pasadena, CA

Show Advanced Search

AboutLoginSign Up

* Sign Up
* Login
* Get Help

Privacy Policy
==============

Spokeo, Inc. (“Spokeo”) provides the website Spokeo.com to you (“You” or “Your”) subject to this [Privacy Policy](https://www.spokeo.com/privacy-policy), its [Terms of Use](https://www.spokeo.com/terms-of-use), and its other policies.

This Privacy Policy describes the way in which Spokeo collects, uses, or shares any information You provide to Spokeo.com or information about Your use of Spokeo.com (“Personal Information”).

Spokeo may change this Privacy Policy at any time. The most current version of this policy can be accessed at [https://www.spokeo.com/privacy-policy](https://www.spokeo.com/privacy-policy). By continuing to access or use Spokeo.com, You accept any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy.

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS POLICY DO NOT USE SPOKEO.COM

**1\. Information Available Through Spokeo.com People Search**

a) Spokeo collects publicly available information for the purpose of making it available to individuals, businesses, and government agencies that use Spokeo’s products and services, including the Spokeo.com people search. Spokeo aggregates the following eight categories of publicly available information:

(i) Consumer Indexes - Records of consumer profiles detailing age, name, address and other demographic details disclosed by consumers to third party survey companies without restriction;

(ii) Phone Directories - Phone numbers drawn from white pages telephone directories;

(iii) Email Databases - Email addresses disclosed by consumers to third party survey companies without restriction;

(iv) Property Records - Public property records from government offices around the country, including real estate deeds and assessor records;

(v) Social Networks - Public social profiles drawn from social networks;

(vi) Court Records - Public criminal records from government offices across the U.S. Contains arrest and most wanted warrants, driving violations, sex offender data and fugitive records;

(vii) Business Directories - Business listings pulled from the yellow pages telephone directories and other public business directories. These listings include name, title, business address, website and email; and

(viii) Vital Statistics - Public records about life events documented by the government, including birth certificates, marriage licenses and death certificates.

(collectively the “Public Information”).

b) Spokeo does not verify and cannot guarantee the accuracy of this Public Information.

c) The Spokeo [Terms of Use](https://www.spokeo.com/terms-of-use-consumer) prohibit users of Spokeo’s products and services from reselling the Public Information disclosed to them through Spokeo’s products and services.

d) Personal Information, such as information that You provide to Spokeo.com or information about Your use of Spokeo.com as further described in Section 2 below, is not part of the Public Information available to users through the Spokeo.com people search.

e) To request that Public Information about You be removed from public listings on Spokeo.com, please use the Remove A Public Listing tool at [https://www.spokeo.com/optout](https://www.spokeo.com/optout). This page also contains information about alternate ways to submit a request for the removal of public listings. This process is only intended to remove listings available to the general public on Spokeo.com, does not apply to listings available to customers of other Spokeo products, does not apply to information collected, processed, sold, or disclosed under certain federal laws such as the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act that are excluded from the scope of state privacy laws, and cannot remove the information from the third-party public sources, such as phone books, social networks, or government records. Spokeo does not allow individuals to opt-out (i.e. suppress display) of court records which pertain to them, unless an Order of Expunction or Sealing is provided. You may email a copy of any such Order to expungement@spokeo.com. Spokeo will only suppress or delete only those records specifically noted in the Order. A conviction may be expunged, but unless the Order also specifies expungement of the associated arrest record, it will remain on Spokeo’s systems. Spokeo reserves the right to disclose Public Information that you have requested be removed to third parties, without notice to You, if required by law, or if Spokeo has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (i) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety; (ii) comply with legal process; or (iii) protect and defend Spokeo’s rights or property. Spokeo also reserves the right to transfer Public Information (including Public Information that you have requested by removed) to any successor-in-interest to the Spokeo business. Spokeo reserves the right to deny or reverse a request for the removal of public listings if Spokeo believes such request was made in a manner that does not comply with its [Terms of Use](https://www.spokeo.com/terms-of-use) or other policies.

**2\. Personal Information Spokeo Collects**

Spokeo collects the following categories of Personal Information:

i) Usage Information. Spokeo collects information about Your use of Spokeo.com. This may include the pages You visit, the links You hover over and click on, and the items You purchase. Spokeo also collects data about Your device such as IP address, mobile phone number, device identifiers, and data about the network, operating system, or software You use to connect to Spokeo’s products and services. Spokeo may utilize a third party service provided by FullStory to collect usage information.

ii) Information From Cookies. Spokeo.com uses cookies, or small text files stored on Your computer, to store data about Your visits. Further information about cookies is available at [https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy](https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy).

iii) Account Information. Spokeo collects information that You provide in creating an account at Spokeo.com. This may include information such as Your name, email address, or phone number and payment data. Spokeo also collects passwords and similar security information used for authentication and account access.

iv) Search History. Spokeo retains a history of the searches You conduct on Spokeo’s products.

v) Submissions, Posts, and Uploads. Spokeo collects information from You when You provide, post, or upload it to Spokeo, such as when You fill out a form, (e.g., a request to contact You) or respond to a survey. If You opt to import Your call log or address book, Spokeo receives Your call log or contacts. Certain features of Spokeo’s products permit You to enter personal information to access Your accounts with third-party websites. In some instances, this information is not stored by Spokeo. For example, You may choose to provide Your email account login credentials to import Your address book contacts into Spokeo.com. Your email account login credentials will only be used for the one-time address book import and will not be stored.

vi) Manually Imported Contact Information. Spokeo collects contact information about You when others import or sync their contacts with Spokeo products.

vii) Manually Entered Login Credentials. Certain features of Spokeo.com must store Your login credentials for other websites or services to function. For example, You may choose to provide Your third-party login credentials to syndicate private content from third-party social networks and websites. Under these circumstances, Your third-party login credentials will be stored only so long as You continue to enable private content syndication from these third-party social networks and websites. Should You terminate Your use of the syndication tool, this information will be deleted within a reasonable period of time following the termination. Your third-party login credentials are hashed and stored with the strictest security standards.

viii) Location Information. When You enable location-based features of Spokeo products, Spokeo may collect location data, such as GPS coordinates. Spokeo may also collect location data derived from Your IP address.

**3\. Use and Sharing of Personal Information**

a) Spokeo may use Personal Information You provide to Spokeo.com to create and maintain Your account, to personalize Your experience, and to send periodic email communications relating to Spokeo’s services, such as purchase receipts, account confirmations, and customer care correspondence, including emails to customers who have abandoned the account setup experience and about searches You have previously performed. Spokeo may use Your search history to provide You updates or notifications on the subjects of Your searches, to suggest other search subjects that may be of interest to You, and to otherwise enhance Your experience in using Spokeo’s products. Spokeo may also use Your search history and other Personal Information to improve Spokeo’s products and services. If You have made or attempted a purchase on Spokeo.com or accepted a trial of any of Spokeo’s premium subscriptions, You will be deemed to have opted-in to receive promotional emails from Spokeo, and Spokeo may use Your Personal Information to send You search tips, promotions, and information about new products Spokeo thinks may be of interest to You.

b) Spokeo uses certain trusted third parties to help us provide, improve, protect, and promote the services offered on Spokeo.com. Spokeo shares Personal Information with these third parties. These third parties will access Your information only to perform tasks on Spokeo’s behalf and in compliance with this Privacy Policy. For example, Spokeo provides payment data that You provide to certain payment processors, solely to effect the sale of products or subscriptions that You have requested, and provides other Personal Information to third party services for purposes such as delivering email communications, providing customer support, and preventing fraudulent transactions. Spokeo may also use a third party service provider to facilitate upload of Your contacts from Your contact management providers, using the OAuth standard whenever possible (If Your contact management providers support the OAuth standard, use of the OAuth standard does not require Spokeo or its third-party service provider to have access to, and Spokeo and its third-party service provider, will not in fact have access to, the passwords that You established with Your contact management providers). Spokeo uses the Google Maps API(s), which is subject to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

c) Spokeo may share IP addresses used to access Spokeo.com with designated third parties for the sole purpose of preventing and detecting fraud. Spokeo may also use services and technologies provided by other companies to assist Spokeo in understanding how You use Spokeo.com. As a result, information about how You use Spokeo.com may be available to these other companies to the extent that their technology collects such information for Spokeo’s use or for purposes of delivering relevant online or mobile advertising to You. Further information is available at: [https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy](https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy) and [https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy](https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy).

d) Spokeo may also share Your Personal Information with advertisers and other third parties who may use it for advertising purposes, including to serve targeted advertising on Spokeo’s websites and mobile applications and on unaffiliated third-party websites. These companies may utilize cookies, pixels, or other technologies to collect user information (e.g., hashed, de-identified data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during Your visits to this and other websites to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to You. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to You based on information about Your online activities on Spokeo’s websites, applications, and/or other websites over time. For example, information collected across multiple sites may enable the ad network to predict Your preferences and show You ads that are likely to be of interest to You. To opt out of these types of ads, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative for information about how to opt-out of interest-based advertising by their members. See [https://www.thenai.org](https://www.thenai.org/) for general information about the NAI and [https://thenai.org/opt-out](https://thenai.org/opt-out) for the opt-out page. You may also visit [https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=E](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=E) to learn about interest-based advertising and how to opt out from online behavioral ads served by some or all participating companies. Please note that You may need to opt out on each device and browser You use to access Spokeo’s websites and applications.

e) Spokeo reserves the right to disclose Personal Information to third parties, without notice to You, if required to do so by law, or if Spokeo has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with legal process served on us; (2) protect and defend Spokeo’s rights or property; or (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety. This disclosure may include Your search query, and may be disclosed to the subject of Your search query, notwithstanding any statements on the Spokeo.com website about confidentiality and notification.

f) Spokeo reserves the right to transfer Personal Information to any successor in interest to the Spokeo business.

g) Spokeo (either directly or via its third party partners) collects anonymized session and anonymized click-tracking data regardless of a computer's Do-Not-Track signal.

h) Spokeo may provide Your search query to third party data vendors in order to fulfill requests You make for certain kinds of reports.

i) Except as specifically noted in this Privacy Policy or at [https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy](https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy) or at [https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy](https://www.spokeo.com/cookie-policy), Spokeo does not sell, exchange, transfer, or give Personal Information to any other company.

**4\. Children’s Privacy**

a) Spokeo.com is directed to people who are at least 18 years old, and Spokeo does not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under the age of 18. If You are aware that Spokeo has collected Personal Information from someone under the age of 18, please alert Spokeo at CustomerCare@spokeo.com and the information will be removed from Spokeo’s systems as soon as is reasonably possible. This policy regarding collection of data from children exceeds the requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.

b) Spokeo does not knowingly aggregate or provide Public Information about people under the age of 18. Spokeo’s email search may return Public Information about children between the ages of 13 and 18 because this Public Information originates from third-party social networking sites and websites that permit children who are 13 years and older to create public profiles. To remove any Spokeo listing, including a listing that contains information about a person under the age of 18, please use the Remove A Listing tool at [https://www.spokeo.com/optout](https://www.spokeo.com/optout).

**5\. Contacting Spokeo**

If You have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at CustomerCare@spokeo.com or mail at 556 S. Fair Oaks Ave., Suite #101-179, Pasadena, CA USA 91105.

**6\. State Privacy Law Disclosure**

a) State consumer privacy laws may provide residents with additional rights regarding consumer information. If You are a resident of California, Your privacy rights are further described in the Notice for California Residents section below.

b) Right to Ask Us Not to Sell (also known as Right to Opt-out)

(i) Right to Opt-out Personal Information – As explained above, Spokeo does not sell Personal Information, such as a name or email address provided when subscribing to Spokeo. Personal Information is not combined for sale with Public Information, as Public Information is not obtained from visitors or subscribers, but is instead obtained from publicly available data sources independent of anything visitors or subscribers may have provided Spokeo.

(ii) Right to Opt-out Public Information – Under all current state privacy laws, Public Information constitutes “publicly available information” that is excluded from the scope of personal data or personal information. However, Spokeo accommodates requests to remove Public Information. Please refer to Section 1e) above for instructions and information about submitting such requests.

c) Right to Know, Correct, and Request Deletion of Personal Information – You have the right to request that Spokeo disclose what Personal Information it collects, uses, and discloses and to request that Spokeo correct it, taking into account the nature and the purposes of the processing of the Personal Information. Except as specifically noted in this Privacy Policy or at [https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy](https://www.spokeo.com/third-party-privacy), Spokeo does not sell, exchange, transfer, or give Personal Information to any other party. You also have the right to request that Spokeo delete the Personal Information it has collected. To make a Right-to-Know, Correction, and/or Deletion request related to Personal Information, [click here](https://www.spokeo.com/privacy/control/account/results) or [call 1 (877) 864-0183](tel:1-877-864-0183) during Spokeo’s business hours. You will be required to log in to Your Spokeo account or provide sufficient matching information for Spokeo to verify Your request. Spokeo cannot delete Personal Information that it is under a legal obligation to maintain or that Spokeo may maintain under specific scenarios specified in the state privacy laws. An authorized agent may make a request on Your behalf. No additional proof will be required from an authorized agent, except that, for Your protection, Spokeo will only disclose the categories of Personal Information collected to authorized agents that make requests through Spokeo’s toll free number.

d) Spokeo will not discriminate against You for exercising Your rights under this section of this Privacy Policy.

e) If You are a resident of Colorado, Connecticut or Virginia, You have the right to appeal a decision denying Your privacy request. You may request an appeal of such a decision by contacting Spokeo at [privacy@spokeo.com](mailto:privacy@spokeo.com). and providing the state You are writing from and documentation You may have regarding the matter You are appealing. In the event Your appeal is denied, Your jurisdiction may allow You to file a complaint with Your state Attorney General’s Office regarding Your concerns with the result of Your appeal request. You may do so by selecting the appropriate link: Colorado [https://coag.gov/file-complaint/](https://coag.gov/file-complaint/), Connecticut [https://portal.ct.gov/AG/Common/Complaint-Form-Landing-page](https://portal.ct.gov/AG/Common/Complaint-Form-Landing-page), and Virginia [https://www.oag.state.va.us/consumer-protection/index.php/file-a-complaint](https://www.oag.state.va.us/consumer-protection/index.php/file-a-complaint).

f) Notice to California Residents:

(i) In addition to the above, the following, intended solely for California residents, concerns Spokeo’s handling of certain personally identifiable and/or personal information as required by the California Online Privacy Protection Act and the California Consumer Privacy Act, as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act (collectively, “CCPA”). If You are a California resident, You may have additional rights where Personal Information is concerned.

(ii) Public Information - Public Information constitutes “publicly available information” that is excluded from personal information under the CCPA. However, Spokeo accommodates requests to remove Public Information. Please refer to Section 1e) above for instructions and information about submitting such requests.

(iii) Categories of Personal Information; Use and Disclosure - The categories of Personal Information that Spokeo obtains or collects are specified in this Privacy Policy and in other locations on the Spokeo.com website. Spokeo and/or its service providers may use Personal Information as specified in this Privacy Policy. Spokeo may disclose Personal Information as specified in this Privacy Policy.

(iv) Sale of Personal Information - As explained above, Spokeo does not sell Personal Information. Personal Information is not combined for sale with Public Information, as Public Information is not obtained from visitors or subscribers, but is instead obtained from publicly available data sources independent of anything visitors or subscribers may have provided Spokeo. As permitted by law and CCPA regulatory guidance, Spokeo may need to share certain limited Personal Information about Your activity, for example through cookies (see above), with third parties in certain instances. You can control these cookies through browser settings, but this limited sharing does not constitute a sale of Personal Information.

(v) You have the right to request that Spokeo disclose what Personal Information it collects, uses, and discloses and to request that Spokeo correct it, taking into account the nature and the purposes of the processing of the Personal Information. You also have the right to request that Spokeo delete the Personal Information it has collected. See Section 6c) above for instructions about how to exercise Your rights to make such requests. You will be required to log in to Your Spokeo account or provide sufficient matching information in order for Spokeo to verify Your request. Spokeo cannot delete Personal Information that it is under a legal obligation to maintain and may also decline to delete Personal Information in certain excluded scenarios that are specified in CCPA. Spokeo will not discriminate against You for exercising Your rights under this section of this Privacy Policy. An authorized agent may make a request on Your behalf. No additional proof will be required from an authorized agent, except that, for Your protection, Spokeo will only disclose the categories of Personal Information collected to authorized agents that make requests through Spokeo’s toll free number.

(vi) From January 1, 2023 through December 31, 2023, with respect to Personal Information, Spokeo:

(i) Received 43 Right to Know Requests, complied in whole or in part with 43 Right to Know Requests, and denied 0.

(ii) Received 23 Requests to Delete, complied in whole or in part with 23 Requests to Delete, and denied 0. For each of these 23 Requests to Delete, certain Personal Information was not deleted pursuant to California Civil Code § 1798.145(a)(1).

(iii) Received 0 Requests to limit the use of Personal Information. Spokeo does not use Personal Information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy.

When such requests with respect to Personal Information are submitted in accordance with the instructions in Section 6c) above, such requests take effect in real time following completion of the request submittal.

Since January 1, 2023, Spokeo has regarded Public Information as “publicly available information” as defined in the California Privacy Rights Act. Nevertheless, as Spokeo has voluntarily done for many years, Spokeo continues to accommodate requests to remove Public Information. Please refer to Section 1e) above for instructions and information about submitting such requests. From January 1, 2023 to December 31, 2023, Spokeo received 687,774 requests to opt-out Public Information (which, again constitutes “publicly available information” as defined in the California Privacy Rights Act), complied in whole or in part with 656,020 of such requests, and denied 31,754 of such requests in whole or in part. When such requests are submitted in accordance with the instructions in Section 1e) above, the Remove A Public Listing tool removes Public Information in real time following completion of the request submittal.

**7\. Specific Clauses for EU Data Subjects**

The following applies only if You are in the European Economic Area or Switzerland (collectively the “EU”):

a) The following clauses only apply to Personal Information You provide to Spokeo.com. To request that Public Information about You be removed from public listings on Spokeo.com, please use the Remove A Public Listing tool at [https://www.spokeo.com/optout](https://www.spokeo.com/optout) to make the request and refer to Section 1e) above for instructions and information. Please be advised that, when a Spokeo profile contains information about an EU data subject, it is typically Public Information that the data subject has himself/herself/themselves provided to a social network and that is or was made public by the data subject. Spokeo does not process personal data for or at the request of any social network, as Spokeo and its data providers obtain the information from publicly available profiles that the data subject has authorized, or did authorize, the social network to make public. As such, in this context, Spokeo is neither a controller nor a processor of the data contained in public listings on Spokeo.com.

b) Spokeo relies upon the following lawful grounds to collect and use Your Personal Information:

(i) It is necessary for the performance of a contract.

(ii) Spokeo’s or a third party’s legitimate interests, including but not limited to, identity verification and fraud prevention.

(iii) Your consent.

c) You may use Your account to access, correct, or change any Personal Information that You have provided to us or that is associated with Your account. You may also email CustomerCare@spokeo.com to request access to, transfer of, and rectification or erasure of Your Personal Information, or restriction of processing, or to object to processing. You will need to specify the nature of Your request and the information that is subject to Your request. Spokeo may require You to submit additional information necessary to verify Your identity and status as an EU data subject. Spokeo will respond to Your request within 30 days.

d) If Spokeo is processing Your Personal Information based upon the lawful ground of Your consent, You have the right to withdraw Your consent for such processing at any time without affecting the lawfulness of the processing based on consent before it is withdrawn. To withdraw consent, email CustomerCare@spokeo.com.

e) If You are an EU data subject and have inquiries about Your Personal Information, please contact Spokeo’s Data Protection Officer at [privacy@spokeo.com](mailto:privacy@spokeo.com).

_Last Revised: July 25th, 2024_

Area Code:

Name:

* * *

Spokeo is not a consumer reporting agency as defined by the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA). Do not use this site to make decisions about credit, employment, tenant screening, or any purpose covered by the FCRA.

Copyright © 2006-2024 Spokeo, Inc.
